Benjamin Grinthal

CONTACT

Address: 9206 Morgan Way, Mount Laurel NJ,

08054

Phone: (732) 616-8142 **Email**: bgrinthal@gmail.-

com

SKILLS

- Computer-Aided Design (CAD)
- MATLAB
- SolidWorks / AutoCAD
- Microsoft Visio
- Management and delegation
- 3D Modeling/ Design
- Product Development
- Mechanical Design
- Teamwork/ Collaboration
- Manufacturing Process
- Engineering support

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Determined mechanical engineering with over 6 years of experience. Seeking to use proven design, problem-solving, and management skills to excel any position. Collaborative team player with track record of delivering multiple, concurrent projects in fast-paced environments.

WORK HISTORY

OSP Engineer 11/2021 to 04/2022

Verizon - Mount Laurel, NJ

- Managed the damage, upgrade, and installation of Verizon's facilities in designated areas
- Coordinate with construction, power companies, and project managers to ensure work is completed in a timely manner
- Work with vendors to increase production and create accurate design for construction to follow
- Represent Verizon in meetings and surveys to solve problems or to expand the network into new locations

Design Engineer, 04/2018 to 11/2021

Byers Engineering Company Inc. - Somerset, NJ

- Design layouts for Verizon's service providing cables through large New York City streets and buildings
- Create CAD drawings using Microsoft Visio and AutoCAD to convey manufacturing and production configurations
- Estimate quantities and cost of materials, equipment, and labor to determine project feasibility
- Use Google Earth and Microsoft Visio to create detailed maps from raw field data of Verizon cable systems through New York streets
- Develop proposals for clients outlining project scope and timeline
- Provide technical guidance, peer review, and mentorship to junior engineers engaged in Fios building designs
- Read and interpret blueprints, technical drawings, schematics, and computer-generated reports
- Travels to location to sketch/verify on field information to use for design

Warehouse Assistant, 02/2017 to 04/2018

Advantech - Somerset, NJ

- Prepared orders for shipment by systematically picking, packing and labeling merchandise.
- Kept all documentation and records accurate and up-to-date with latest data to prevent errors in processing or delivery.
- Moved pallets to and from trucks and around warehouse with forklifts to stay on top of demanding schedules.

Design Engineer Intern, 06/2011 to 12/2016

RotorClip Company - Somerset, NJ

- Perform tolerance analysis to support success in high-volume heat treatment product manufacturing
- Operate tensile and hardness testing machines to perform spot analysis on products
- Use Solidworks to design tools for creating company retaining rings
- Design retaining rings meeting company and customer tolerance and material standards
- Document drawing edits using Engineering Change Notices (ECN)

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science: Mechanical Engineering, 05/2016 **Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey** - New Brunswick, NJ

Aerospace Engineering Certificate